なっ！　あれは!?
That's...
Episode 12
Absent Thee
from Felicity Awhile
（不破真広）絶園の魔法使い？
The mage of Exodus?
Is there really such a person?
そんなの
本当にいるのかよ!?
（葉風）私の誕生は
はじまりの樹の覚醒が→
My birth means that the revival of the Tree of Genesis is getting closer.
近づいた証しであり→
My role is to decide when it will fully revive.
私は　その完全覚醒のときを→
決める役割を担わされている。→
（通信）私が
しかるべき時機と意志のもと→
Unless I decide that it is time
一定の手続きを踏まんかぎり
はじまりの樹の完全覚醒はならん。
and perform the necessary procedures,
the Tree of Genesis cannot be completely resurrected.
（葉風）
だからこそ　左門は　私を封じ→
That's why Samon sealed me away,
完全覚醒を遅らせようとしたのだ。
to try and delay the revival.
（滝川吉野）けど　そんな
大きな役割を　なぜ葉風さんに？
But why were you given such a huge task, Ms. Hakaze?
（葉風）神とても
覚醒という大きな変動を→
It may be a god,
but it does not allow a change as drastic as its resurrection to be decided by its own whim.
己の勝手なときに起こすのは
よしとせん。
私は　人の代表として→
I have been chosen to represent humanity,
to decide when the time for revival is right.
そのときを
判断する役割を与えられたのだ。
そんな　はじまりの樹が
現在の文明を食い尽くし→
There is no way that the Tree of Genesis is such a cruel deity
現存生物を死滅させるといった
無慈悲な存在であるはずがない！
that it would devour all of civilization and doom all living creatures!
（左門）しかし　姫様
あなたは　はじまりの樹を盲信し→
However, Princess...
You have blind faith in the Tree of Genesis
危険性など
僅かも顧みられない！→
and will not see its potential threat.
（通信）そんな　あなたに
正しい意志と時機が→
How can you truly determine the appropriate time for the Tree's revival?
お分かりになると言えますか？→
The Tree of Genesis putting its fate in the hands of mere mortals is an illusion.
はじまりの樹が
人の意志に委ねているなど→
まやかしにすぎません！
絶園の樹を見張らせる鎖部一族を
従わせやすくするため→
It only made us believe we had such privilege to guarantee our dedication
そのような特権があると
思わせただけです！
to the task of keeping watch over the Tree of Exodus!
I don't care about any of that!
そういうのは　どうでもいい！
Is there or is there not
絶園の魔法使いは
いるのか!?　いねぇのか!?
a mage of Exodus?
絶園の樹が
己の復活を感じたとき→
As the Tree of Exodus felt its revival approach,
I cannot say it is impossible that a mage of Exodus could have been created,
はじまりの樹の覚醒に合わせて→
姫様が　お生まれになったように→
絶園の魔法使いが
生まれた可能性はないでもない。→
in the same way the princess was born.
However,
しかし　その絶園の魔法使いが→
neither can it be said that this mage of Exodus is the one
お前の妹を殺した犯人とは
まだ言えん！
that killed your sister!
けどよ
絶園の魔法使いが犯人なら→
But if the mage of Exodus is the murderer,
そいつが　はじまりの樹に操られて
愛花を殺したって仮説は→
the theory that the Tree of Genesis controlled that person to kill my sister
no longer stands, does it?
成り立たないんじゃねぇか？
In this world,
絶園の樹は　この世で唯一→
only the Tree of Exodus has the power to exceed the Tree of Genesis.
はじまりの樹の理を
超える力を持つ。
なら　その分身である者が→
So it's hard to imagine
はじまりの樹に操られるなんて
考えにくい。
that the Tree of Genesis could control the other one's avatar.
現に　はじまりの樹の魔法探査にも
引っ掛かってないんだ。
Moreover, the avatar wouldn't be snared by the
Tree of Genesis's magical investigation either.
だとしたら→
If that's the case,
it means that the mage of Exodus just happened to kill Aika.
絶園の魔法使いが
たまたま　愛花を殺し→
The Tree of Genesis then saw an opportunity
それを利用できると考えた
はじまりの樹が→
俺と葉風を結び付けた…
って考えた方が自然になるな。
and put me in touch with Hakaze.
That would be the reasonable conclusion to draw.
それなら　愛花ちゃんの死に
はじまりの樹は関係ない。
If we use that theory,
then the Tree of Genesis would have nothing to do with Aika's death.
逆に　絶園の樹の方に
大きく責任があるってことになる。
In fact, it would imply that the Tree of Exodus was largely responsible.
And if a mage of Exodus has been born in response to the Tree of Exodus's revival,
そして　絶園の樹の復活を感じて→
絶園の魔法使いが
生まれたのなら…。
then you, Kusaribe Samon, who has sped up the Tree's revival,
その復活を
積極的に進めた鎖部左門→
お前も　間接的に
愛花の死に手を貸したことになる。
can be considered to have had a hand in Aika's death, as well.
（心の声）≪そうだ≫
He's right.
Everything's been turned on its head.
≪すべてが　ひっくり返る≫
Samon's logic for fighting the Tree of Genesis
≪左門の　はじまりの樹を
倒すべきという理屈は→
has been applied to Mahiro
fighting the Tree of Exodus instead.
そのまま　真広が　絶園の樹を
倒すという理屈に反転される≫
Kusaribe Samon has lost.
≪鎖部左門の負けだ≫
It appears that this is over, Samon.
（葉風・通信）
詰んだようだな　左門。→
あとは　私が供物を見つけ→
All that remains is for me to find the offering,
and return to your time.
そちらに戻るのみ。
Can this really be allowed to happen?
（左門）
≪こんなことがあっていいのか？≫
≪逆転を期して放った
自らの理論に→
The theory I'd revealed in order to mount a comeback
ものの見事に
返り討たれるとは…≫
has instead been turned completely against me!
≪これが
はじまりの樹に支配された→
Is this the logic of the world
世界の理なのか!?≫
ruled by the Tree of Genesis?
（早河）どういうことだ？
（部下）新たに発生した樹は→
What's going on?
It's been reported that the newly observed tree
appears to be absorbing metallicized life forms.
金属化した生物を
吸収しているように見えると…。
（早河）≪今までのデータにないぞ
こんな現象≫
This didn't happen before.
Reporting!
（局員）報告！
（早河）なんだ？
What is it?
The plant-like object is turning all humans
and man-made objects along its path into ash.
（局員）植物状の物体は
接触した建造物や人工物を→
すべて塵にしています！
文明を食らっているのか？
It's devouring civilization?
（山本）
はじまりの樹って…　あれが？
Is that really
the Tree of Genesis?
Yes, though that is merely a shadow of its true self.
（潤一郎）ええ。　ただし
ごくごく一部にすぎないでしょう。
Mr. Junichiro,
（夏村）潤一郎殿→
本当に　はじまりの樹が
覚醒したのですか？
has the Tree of Genesis truly revived?
As far as I know, Hakaze hasn't approved it.
（潤一郎）葉風ちゃんは　その決定を
行っていないはずだけど…。
≪それとも　これもまた
何か必然の出来事なのか？≫
Or is this yet another inevitable event?
≪左門の負けは確定した≫
Samon's defeat has been decided.
≪こうなれば
孤島にある供物の隠し場所を→
At this point, we should make him tell us where the offering is on the island.
しゃべらせるべきだ。　なのに→
So then,
why aren't you making a move, Mahiro?
なぜ動かないんだ　真広≫
I don't like it.
≪気に入らねぇ≫
Things are working out too well for Hakaze.
≪葉風にとって
うまくいきすぎてやがる≫
What kind of miracle is this,
≪こんなきれいに
逆転が決まるなんて→
that the reversal goes so well?
どんな奇跡だよ≫
Even if I were to help Samon,
≪左門に手を貸しても
愛花を殺した犯人は見つからねぇ≫
I wouldn't be able to find Aika's killer.
≪それどころか　左門の野郎が→
Not only that,
but Samon may be part of the reason she died.
愛花の殺された
原因かもしれねぇくらいだ≫
≪だが→
But if this is all something that the Tree of Genesis willed to happen,
もし　これが　はじまりの樹の
仕組んだことなら→
perhaps it made it seem like there was a mage of Exodus,
あたかも　絶園の魔法使いが
実在するかのように見せかけ→
to force me to side with Hakaze.
俺が葉風に肩入れする状況を
作ったって可能性もある≫
≪確かに　そうだ≫
It's certainly true.
≪偽らないまでも　魔法探査に
引っ掛からないようにするだけで→
The Tree may have simply made it look as though a mage of Exodus exists
絶園の魔法使いがいるかのように
錯覚させることは可能≫
by shielding the perpetrator from the web of magic...
But if the Tree of Genesis is behind this,
≪はじまりの樹が犯人なら→
shouldn't Hakaze be the one I shoot?
俺の討つべき相手は
葉風じゃねぇのか？≫
≪けど　今も葉風さんは
必死に供物を探している≫
But even now, Ms. Hakaze is desperately looking for the offering.
If Ms. Hakaze is the true culprit,
≪もし本当に
はじまりの樹が犯人なら→
もっと簡単に
供物が見つかってるはずだ≫
she should have been able to find it far more easily.
Will I really be able
≪葉風に手を貸して　本当に→
to track down the killer by siding with Hakaze?
犯人にたどりつけるのか？≫
The killer could be the Tree of Genesis.
≪犯人は　はじまりの樹かも
しれねぇんだぞ≫
≪真広　今は　はじまりの樹を…→
Mahiro, right now, we should believe in the Tree of Gen—
いや　葉風さんを信じるべきだ≫
No, we should believe in Ms. Hakaze.
≪もはや　私に打つ手はない≫
There is nothing I can do.
≪だが→
But...
あの少年が
魔具を持ったまま動かんのなら→
As long as that boy holds the talisman without firing it,
まだ望みはある≫
there is still hope.
If the Tree of Exodus can be revived before the princess returns,
≪姫様が戻る前に
絶園の樹復活が間に合えば→
we may yet manage to win.
勝てないことはない≫
（葉風）
≪左門　供物をどこに隠した!?≫
Samon, where did you hide the offering?!
（左門）≪姫様→
Princess,
with only the information you have, it will take you at least two—
今ある情報だけで
供物を見つけるのには　２時間…→
no, perhaps one hour to find it.
いや
１時間は　最低かかるはずです≫
≪こればかりは　自分で見つける≫
I shall find it on my own.
≪はじまりの樹に祈りはせん！≫
I will not pray to the Tree of Genesis!
（左門）
≪その間　何事もなく過ぎれば→
Provided nothing else interferes during that time,
絶園の樹の復活が
間に合う希望はある≫
there is still hope that the Tree of Exodus will be revived in time!
Even if the Tree of Genesis
≪たとえ
本当に　はじまりの樹が→
really did cause Mahiro's sister's death,
真広の妹の死を
招いたのだとしても→
I must go back there!
私は　そちらに戻らねばならん≫
If I don't, I cannot do anything!
≪戻らねば　何もできん≫
I cannot make amends...
≪何も償えん≫
≪いや　はじまりの樹といえど→
No...
Even if it is the Tree of Genesis,
それほど　精緻に
理を　操れるものなのか？≫
does it really wield that much power over logic?
≪あくまで　偶然が重なって→
Shouldn't I consider all of this just a series of coincidences?
そんな状況が作られたと
考えるべきではないのか？≫
≪はじまりの樹が　そこまで
都合よく奇跡を呼べるのなら→
If the Tree of Genesis
could conjure miracles in my favor so easily,
とうに　供物は
見つかっているはずではないか≫
shouldn't I have found the offering by now?
≪これほどまでに　私が求め→
It wishes me to find it, and yet...
見つかるのを
望んでいるというのに…≫
≪そうだ…　やはり→
Right.
It couldn't have arranged the circumstances of Mahiro's sister's death.
はじまりの樹が　真広の妹の死を
作り出したわけでは…≫
≪ゴオオォーーー…
≪ドーーン！
≪そんな…≫
No.
≪まさか…≫
Impossible.
This can't be—
≪そんなことが…≫
（葉風）ミサイル？→
A missile?
How did such a product of civilization
こんな文明の産物が
なぜ　都合よく私のもとに…。
appear before me so easily?
≪左門の隠した供物は
容易に見つからない≫
I was having trouble finding the offering Samon hid,
≪ならばと　私に
まったく別の供物を送り届けたか≫
so it sent me another instead.
≪はじまりの樹が
ここまで　理を操れるのなら→
If the Tree of Genesis can manipulate the natural order to this degree,
it's reasonable to assume it could have killed
高校生の妹一人を
都合のよいときに殺すなど→
a simple high school student's sister.
造作もないではないか…≫
（通信）葉風さん？→
Ms. Hakaze,
どうかしましたか？
is something wrong?
（葉風）いや　供物が手に入った。
（通信）えっ？
No.
I found the offering.
Huh?
そちらに戻るぞ。
I'm coming back.
吉野　そちらの人形を
私の骨に掛けろ。→
Yoshino, put the doll close to my skeleton.
骨と人形　２つで位置を確定する。
I will determine the location
using the skeleton and the doll.
はい　分かりました。
Understood.
（葉風）≪ふざけるな≫
Don't be foolish.
≪ここで折れてなるものか≫
I cannot waver here!
（通信）準備できました。
It's ready.
Even if the Tree of Genesis doesn't desire it,
≪たとえ　それが　はじまりの樹が
望まぬことであっても→
I will find the one who killed Mahiro's sister,
真広の妹を殺した犯人は
必ず見つけてやる≫
no matter what.
≪私は　私のために戦った者を
決して裏切らん≫
I will never betray one who fought for my sake.
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹！→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
始まりにありし　はじまりの樹→
tree that has existed since the beginning, Tree of Genesis.
我が名は　鎖部葉風。
My name is Kusaribe Hakaze.
≪私は戻る　ここより先へ！≫
I am returning, returning to the future.
（葉風）時の狭間を越えるため→
To travel through time, by my proud name, hear my wish!
かくも気高き名において
聞き届けよ！
なんだ!?
What?
こっ　これは…。
Th-This is...
≪時間の檻が…≫
The prison of time...
It's been broken.
≪破れた！≫
（葉風）
ああ…　こちらは冬だったか。
Oh, so it's winter here.
It seems I'll be cold in my present state.
（葉風）
さすがに　これでは寒いな。→
我が名は　鎖部葉風。
I am Kusaribe Hakaze,
はじまりの姫宮。
the Princess of Genesis.
２年の時を越え　帰って来たぞ。
I've traveled two years through time to return.
Why are you naked, Ms. Hakaze?
葉風さん　なんで裸なんですか!?
（葉風）着ているものまで
再構成する余裕などあるか。
I didn't have enough time to regenerate clothes on top of everything else.
（葉風）あれが真広か。→
So that's Mahiro?
なるほど　いかにもな顔つきだな。
だが→
He's exactly as I imagined.
On the other hand, Yoshino...
吉野　貴様は随分　幼い感じだな。
You look surprisingly young.
ああも　抜け目なく立ち回れる
悪党には見えんぞ？
Nothing like the villain your actions have made you out to be.
But I'm not a villain.
いやいや　悪党じゃありませんって。
ん？
本物の銃ではないか。
This looks like a real gun to me.
貴様　やはり悪党であろう。
Surely you must be a villain.
I'm telling you I'm not.
だから違いますって。
（葉風）左門　説明は不要であろう。
Samon, I doubt an explanation is necessary.
私に従え。→
Obey me.
だが
貴様が間違っているかどうか→
However, in my current state,
今の私には分からん。→
I cannot determine if you are right or wrong.
これから
何を選び　何をなすべきか→
We must discuss what we should choose,
互いに話し合わねばなるまい。→
and what must be done from here on.
I am in no rush to dispose of the Tree of Exodus.
絶園の樹の処置も　急ぐ気はない。
（葉風）真広→
Mahiro?
かようなことになったが
約束は守る。
These are our circumstances, but I will keep my promise.
はじまりの樹の企みが
裏にあろうと→
Even if the Tree of Genesis truly is behind this,
必ず　貴様の前に
犯人をひれ伏せさせる。
I shall, without fail, bring the killer before you.
今は　それで　こらえてくれ。
Please accept this for now.
I am protected by the world's logic
私は　世の理の加護を受け
時間さえ越えた者だぞ？→
and have even traveled through time.
この私が願うならば→
If I were to wish it,
たとえ　犯人が絶園の樹であろうと
見つけられんわけがない。→
even should the Tree of Exodus be the killer,
there's no reason I couldn't find the culprit.
見つけられんなら　それは
はじまりの樹が犯人のときだけだ。
The only scenario in which I couldn't
would be if the Tree of Genesis were the killer.
そのときは　私を殺せ。
If that turns out to be the case, kill me.
貴様の妹を殺したのは
私も同然だ！
It would mean that I killed your sister!
ふっ　分かったよ。　なら　吉野→
All right.
Well, Yoshino,
お前も
愛花の彼氏を教えるって約束…。
you should keep your promise about Aika's boyf—
（哲馬・通信）左門殿！
哲馬か！　一体　何があった!?
Mr. Samon!
Tetsuma? What's going on?
（哲馬）はじまりの樹の強襲です！
結界が破られます！
The Tree of Genesis has initiated an assault!
The barrier will be broken!
（左門・通信）はじまりの樹!?
The Tree of Genesis?
（山本）結界が　あんなに簡単に!?
（潤一郎）あの結界自体→
It penetrated the barrier that easily?
The barrier itself
はじまりの樹の力を借りて
作ったものですから。
was made with the Tree of Genesis's aid.
（夏村）結界は
絶園の樹の制御もしていました。
The barrier was controlling the Tree of Exodus.
それを
いきなり消失させるなど…。
If that barrier were to be suddenly obliterated—
潤一郎殿　一体
これから　どうなるのです!?
Mr. Junichiro, what will happen now?
分からない。　ただ→
I don't know.
I only know
これからは嵐だ。
that a storm is coming.
あっ！
（左門）はじまりの樹の覚醒か!?
Is the Tree of Genesis reviving?
葉風さんが!?
いや　私は何も命じていない！
Is this your doing, Ms. Hakaze?
No, I haven't willed any of this to happen.
Mr. Samon,
左門殿！
絶園の樹は　我々の制御を離れ→
the Tree of Exodus is attempting to break out of our control
はじまりの樹に
応戦しようとしています！
and attack the Tree of Genesis!
Mr. Samon, what are your orders?!
左門殿　ご指示を!!　左門殿!!
Mr. Samon!
どうした!?　哲馬～!!
What's wrong? Tetsuma!
（山本）これは　現実感ないわ…。
This can't be real...
（夏村）このままでは
狂嵐した絶園の樹によって→
At this rate, the Tree of Exodus will go berserk
富士山麓は壊滅…→
and destroy the entire area around Mt. Fuji.
Actually, this storm of destruction may end up
いえ　列島すら分断させかねない
破壊の嵐が…。
tearing the entire country apart.
（潤一郎）かもしれないね。
It may be.
でも　はじまりの樹は
これで終わったわけじゃない。
But the Tree of Genesis isn't done yet.
（山本）絶園の樹を食ってる!?
Is it eating the Tree of Exodus?
防御！
Defense!
But Mr. Junichiro,
しかし　潤一郎殿→
姫様が
完全に覚醒を行っていないゆえ→
since the princess hasn't conducted the final steps for the revival,
現状では　絶園の樹が優勢では？
shouldn't the Tree of Exodus have the upper hand?
Judging by this area, yes.
ここだけ見ればね。
けど　たぶん→
But the Tree of Genesis has most likely begun its revival across the world.
はじまりの樹は
世界中で覚醒を始めていると思う。
パリでもか！
急いで確認しろ　今すぐに！
In Thailand, too?
Get a confirmation! Immediately!
≪ニューヨークに巨大な樹が出現！
≫ダメだ　情報が足りない！
A giant tree has appeared in New York!
It's no good! There's not enough information!
≪あの文明を食ってる樹は→
So that civilization-devouring tree
国内だけの現象じゃないのか!?≫
wasn't limited to this country alone?
我が名において聞き届けよ。
Hear my name, and grant my wish!
左門　復活の儀式は
どこでやっている？
Samon!
Where are they conducting the revival ceremony?
それは…。
儀式の場に相当量の供物があろう。
I can't—
There must be quite a few offerings at the site!
それを使って
私が絶園の樹を抑える。→
I will use them to suppress the Tree of Exodus.
Simultaneously, I will halt the Tree of Genesis's revival.
同時に
はじまりの樹の覚醒を止める。
信じろ！　はじまりの樹を
このまま　完全覚醒させはせん！
Believe me!
I will not attempt to fully revive the Tree of Genesis now!
分かりました…。
All right then.
（局員）地震か!?
（局員）でかいぞ！
An earthquake?
It's huge!
（早河）世界の…　関節が外れた…。
The world is going insane...
真広　その魔具をよこせ。→
Mahiro, give me that talisman.
I will use it as an offering
それを供物にし直し
ここの防御壁を強化する。
to strengthen the defense here.
I'll strengthen this barrier enough that it will hold,
even if the Tree of Exodus attacks.
この結界は　絶園の樹に
直撃されても保つようにしておく。
私が大樹を鎮めに行っている間
貴様たちは　ここを動くな。
While I calm the great tree, you two stay here.
はぁ…　分かったよ。
All right.
さっさと鎮めてきやがれ！
Hurry and calm it down.
（葉風）吉野。
えっ？
Yoshino.
I will be sure to thank you.
貴様には　あとで　必ず礼を…。
（葉風）吉野～!!
吉野!!
Yoshino!
少年！　不用意に動くな！
Young man, do not move!
（葉風）真広!!
Mahiro!
（山本）あっ…　彼は　どこ？
Where'd he go?
潤一郎殿は　そういう方です。
Mr. Junichiro is like that.
どうにも捉えどころのない…　ん？
He's rather hard to read.
（山本）ここは　やばそうね。
あなたは　どうするの？
It's getting too dangerous here.
What are you going to do?
（夏村）鎖部夏村。
（山本）えっ？
Kusaribe Natsumura.
私の名前です。
That is my name.
（山本）もし生き残れたら　お互い→
If we survive this,
it seems we'll have a lot to talk about.
腹を割って話す必要がありそうね。
（夏村）独断では答えかねます。
I am not at personal liberty to make that decision.
（左門）≪なんということだ…≫
How horrible...
≪姫様が戻られた途端
もはや　二人は→
Once the princess returned,
these two were disposed of as though
they were deemed no longer necessary.
用済みとばかりに
排除された≫
≪偶然か？　いや→
Is it a coincidence?
Or...
それとも　これが→
Could this be the logic of the Tree of Genesis?
はじまりの樹の理なのか？≫
（葉風）
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹！
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree.
まだ我の言葉を
聞き届ける意思があるのなら→
If you still intend to heed my words,
答えよ！
answer!
姫様　そっ　それを使っては…。
（葉風）左門！
Princess, if you use that—
Samon!
お前は　真広を助けろ！
私は　これから→
You save Mahiro!
I will heal Yoshino as I head to the ritual site.
吉野の体を修復しながら
儀式場へ向かう！→
You must save him, do you understand?
いいか　絶対に助けろ！→
真広に何かあったら
許さん！→
I won't forgive you if anything happens to him!
許さんからな!!
はい！→
I will never forgive you!
Understood.
（葉風）≪吉野　死なせはせん≫
Yoshino, I will not let you die.
≪決して死なせんぞ≫
I will not!
≪分からん≫
I don't know...
≪はじまりの樹は→
What does
一体　私に　何を
望んでいるのだ≫
the Tree of Genesis wish of me?
Oh, that cry did knock against my very heart!
あの叫びが
胸を打つ！→
かわいそうに」。
Poor souls,
「みんな
溺れてしまった！」。
they perished.
Had I been any god of power,
「私がもし力のある
神様だったなら→
I would have sunk the sea within the earth
海なんか
陸の下に沈めてしまったのに」。
「そして　あの立派な船も→
or ere it should the good ship so have swallowed
乗っていた人たちも→
海に呑み込ませはしなかった」。
and the fraughting souls within her.
While Aika was alive, I never got to ...
The softness of her skin, her warmth.
I never got to know them.
They all died.
The Tree of Genesis swallowed them all up.
Fuwa Mahiro,
could you kill Takigawa Yoshino?
（子供の吉野）
死んだよ。　みんな死んじゃった。→
Oh, that's probably about me.
はじまりの樹が
全部　飲み込んじゃったんだ。
Episode 13
The Reason of Dreams